# **Angelo Ocana Martins**

Address: Ottawa, ON E-mail: angeloocana@gmail.com

Phone: (613) 558-9571 Site: angeloocana.com

Github: github.com/angeloocana Pluralsight: pluralsight.com/profile/ocanaangelo

# Objective

Looking for a remote Senior Javascript Full-stack Developer (React, Nodejs, and Typescript).

#### About Me

With 14 years of web development experience, I have worked with many technologies since pure javascript/html applications, flash/actionscript, jquery, php, c# (web forms / mvc), angular, react (react-native), nodejs, graphql, postgress, mysql, sql server and many other technologies.

Lately, I have been passionate about React, Typescript, Functional Programming and TDD (Test Driven Development).

# Work Experience

## 2018 – Present Kinaxis

### **Principal Developer**

- Design and architect mono repo for a large typescript and react web application.
- Constantly improving performance and tracking memory leaks.
- Created own state management library inspired by redux, reselect and recoil.
- Mentor of junior developers, and always providing help to the whole team.
- Presented many internal Tech talks.

Technologies: React, Typescript, Redux, RxJS, Angular, C#, .net MVC, TDD, Jest/Jasmine, Webpack, styled-components, SASS, testcafe, ramda.

### 2007, 2015 - 2018 Freelancer

#### Senior Full-stack Developer | Latest Projects:

• budbuds.us

Coding | React Native, Redux, Graphql, Nodejs, Postgres, Redis and Docker.

tic-tac-toe-ai.surge.sh

Design and Coding | Html Canvas, React, Jest, Graphql, Nodejs, and Gatsby.

angeloocana.com

Design and Coding | React, Jest, Graphql, Nodejs, and Gatsby.

novoterritorio.azurewebsites.net

Coding | D3, Angular, Ionic, TypeScript, Jasmine, C#, MongoDB, Azure, SASS, and Gulp.

• staffgeist.com

Coding | Angular, Ionic, TypeScript, Jasmine, C#, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Azure, SASS, and Gulp.

• <u>jumpoverjump.com</u>

Design and Coding | Angular, Ionic, Jasmine, C#, MongoDB, Azure, SASS, and Gulp.

## 2011 – 2015 POL, Peela, Total On Demand

#### **Lead Senior C# Software Developer**

- Developed web platform for Small-Medium marketing and endomarketing campaigns,
  5-8 projects every year. 5K-9Million Users.
- Created their own e-commerce platform.
- Provided consultations to extract clients needs and develop strategies.

Technologies: Javascript, C#, .net MVC, Structuremap, Web Forms, JQuery, SQL Server, Postgres, DDD, TDD, Lucene, Elasticsearch, RabbitMQ, Heroku and Amazon AWS.

Clients: Loreal, Johnson, Sony, Vivo Telefonica, Volkswagen, Walmart, BASF, Net, FMC, FTD, Sky, OI, BRF, Syngenta, Cury, Tenda, B2W, Magazine Luiza, FastShop, ...et al.

# 2010 –2011 Empresário Cobrança

### **Lead C# Software Developer**

- Developed web platform to manage debt collection.
- Worked with complex mathematical algorithms to calculate interest rates.
- Created company's own barcode generation software.
- Development of internal Human Resources systems.
- Building access control system using webcams.
- Developed an internal financial control system.
- Wrote performative queries to work with a 500GB SQL Server database over millions of rows.

Technologies: Javascript, C#, WCF, WPF, WebForms, Windows Forms, Windows Services, EXT.Net, Jquery, and SQL Server.

# 2010 –2010 Media W

## **C# Software Developer**

Developed POS Desktop Terminal following government regulations.

Technologies: C#, Windows Forms, and MySQL

## 2008 – 2010 Upgrade Consultoria

## Junior C# Software Developer

- PriManager Developing web platform to manage large-scale construction environments.
- FDE Web platform for managing public schools in São Paulo/BR.
- Developed their own ERP & CRM.

Technologies: Javascript, C#, Webforms, Telerik, JQuery, Web Services, Windows Services, Flash, Action Script, and SQL Server.

# Education

2012 – Present Pluralsight

Design and Technology

pluralsight.com/profile/ocanaangelo

2013 – 2014 UNIP - Universidade Paulista

Analysis and System Development

2011 - 2010 FIAP — Faculdade de Informática e Administração Paulista

Analysis and System Development

2007 - 2009 **FIEB** 

Web Design with Emphasis on Digital Media

# Languages

EnglishPortugueseFrenchSpanishFluentNativeBasicProficient